A Guide to the Dancin' Unlimited Jazz Dance Company Collection, 1990-2016
Virginia Room, Fairfax County Public Library
The Dancin' Unlimited Jazz Dance Company Collection, 1990-2016
Fairfax County Public Library
MSS 05-81
1.0 linear feet
The Dancin’ Unlimited Jazz Dance Company Collection consists of 2.0 linear feet and spans the years 1990-2016. Items include board of director documents, artistic director information, meeting minutes, marketing strategies, show programs and flyers, grant applications, news articles, press releases and printed out blog posts.
Edwards, Lea (1950-)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None
Acquisition Information
Donated by Lea Edwards, May 2022.
Historical and Biographical Information
In 1973, Robert Thoma founded Dancin’ Unlimited in Fairfax, Virginia as the only professional jazz dance company in Fairfax County. Originally called the Dance Theatre Company of Northern Virginia, the company changed its name to Dancin’ Unlimited in 1982 under the direction of Artistic Director, Marilyn York. Dancin’ Unlimited is a non-profit organization and member of the Virginia Dance Coalition and the Northeast Regional Ballet Association. Dancers join only through audition and perform around the Washington metropolitan area. In 1985, Dancin’ Unlimited began its annual Jazz and Tap Dance Festival and continues to organize educational workshops, festivals, and performances with the support of the Arts Council of Fairfax County.
Scope and Content
The Dancin’ Unlimited Jazz Dance Company Collection consists of 2.0 linear feet and spans the years 1990-2016. Items include board of director documents, artistic director information, meeting minutes, marketing strategies, show programs and flyers, grant applications, news articles, press releases and printed out blog posts. Subjects covered are events and operations of the Dancin’ Unlimited Jazz Dance Company.
Series 1: Jazz and Tap Fest, 1990-2015, Box 1
Contains all materials related to planning Dancin’ Unlimited’s annual jazz dance festival including paperwork for advertising such as programs, flyers, scripts, and to do lists.
Series 2: Marketing Files, 2008-2016, Box 1-2
Contains all materials related to Dancin’ Unlimited’s marketing strategies and guidelines including audience analysis reports developed through surveys, dancer and artistic director biographies, grant and donation paperwork, company profile documents, long term plans, press releases, repertoire and program highlight lists, and social media and web design layouts.
Series 3: Meeting Files, 2006-2016, Box 2
Contains all materials related to company meetings including minutes, business policy documents, news articles, bylaws, long term goals, fiscal year planning, strategy ideas, IRS 501(c)(3) tax exempt documentation, website registration, and grant application paperwork.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
None
None
Index Terms
Dance -- Virginia -- Fairfax County; Dancin' Unlimited Jazz Dance Company (Fairfax, VA)
Container List
- Series 1: Jazz and Tap Fest, 1990-2015
  - Actions - Week Of, 2007-2012
  - Advertising, 2004-2015
  - Announcement Scripts, Undated
  - Planning, 2007-2011
  - Programs and Flyers, 1990-2015
- Series 2: Marketing Files, 2008-2016
  - Audience Analysis, 2009-2013
  - Bios - Dancers, 2005-2010
  - Branding Questionnaire, 2012
  - Campaign Planning, 2009-2013
  - Dance Community, 2010
  - Donation Envelope, Undated
  - Grant Materials, 2011-2012
  - History of Dance, Undated
  - Long Range Plan, 2008-2013
  - Marilyn York, 2010
  - Marketing Packet, 2008
  - Organization Information, 2007
  - Press Releases, 2009-2016
  - Profile Info, 2010-2011
  - Programs, 2011
  - Repertoire, 2006
  - Sample Letters, 2008-2016
  - Script Contact Sheet, Undated
  - Studio Show, 2010
  - Social Media, 2010-2014
  - Surveys, 2008-2012
  - Website Layout, 2010
- Series 3: Meeting Files, 2005-2016
  - Business Policies and Planning, 2010-2015
  - Editorials, Essays, and Articles, 2010-2013
  - Grant Applications, 2010-2016
  - Minutes, 2006
  - Minutes, 2007
  - Minutes, 2008
  - Minutes, 2009
  - Minutes, 2010
  - Minutes, 2011
  - Minutes, 2012
  - Minutes, 2013
  - Minutes, 2014
  - Performance and Workshop Planning, 2009-2014
  - Strategy and Business Materials, 2005-2015